MARC H. WEINER

Software Engineer, Systems Engineer, UX Architect

mhweiner.com github.com/mhweiner mhweiner234@gmail.com (845) 558-8917

I design and build things that solve problems. I am an advocate for testable code, modularity, simplicity, readability, reliability, and understanding of the real problem. I embrace practicality and iteration. I am research-driven and excel at optimizing processes and improving efficiency.

SKILLS

Javascript (ES5/ES6), Typescript, HTML5/CSS3, PHP, C++, Java, NodeJS, React, MySQL, MongoDB, Docker/Kuberneties, Full-Stack, MoA, REST API, R&D, Architecture & Strategy, Process & Performance Optimization, BA, Requirement Gathering, Build & Release Tooling, BDD/TDD, Responsive Design, UX Architecture, SDLC, Unix Programming, Scripting, CentOS, Sketch, Adobe CC, Leadership, Mentorship, Agile, Hiring/Team Building

EXPERIENCE

Elemental Cognition, New York, NY Sr. Software Engineer

Mar 2018 - Feb 2019

- Led UX, design, architecture and development of user interface to EC's proprietary AI machine.
- Reported directly to CEO.
- Tech: React, Typescript, Node, ES6 Javascript, HTML5/CSS3

Shutterstock, New York, NY

Jun 2017 - Nov 2017

Sr. Software Engineer (Consultant)

- Architected and wrote the majority of API service that powers all of Shutterstock's enterprise e-commerce.
- Worked with other stakeholder teams to gather technical requirements.
- Optimized performance issues with legacy system and designed new architecture.
- Led API design and technical documentation.
- Established design patterns throughout the application, including testing policy, procedures, and philosophy.
- Tech: ES6, node.js REST API, Behavior Driven Development (BDD), MoA

Ciro, New York, NY

May 2016 - Jun 2017

Founder

- Founded company aimed at solving communication and organizational inefficiencies in development teams. http://ciroapp.com
- Full-Stack Development, UI/UX Design, Dev-Ops
- Tech: PHP7, Docker, Kuberneties, Javascript, HTML5/CSS3, MoA, NodeJS, Real-Time, DigitalOcean

Advizr, New York, NY

Apr 2014 - May 2016

Director of Front-End Technology, UX

- As the first full-time developer hire, led the architecture, UX, and front-end development of award-winning application from the ground up.
- Helped build a small team of developers, freelancers, and managed a creative agency.
- Recognized as Best Client-Facing Technology of 2015 by FFPAD
- Acquired in 2019 by Orion Advisor Services
- Tech: Fully-responsive, Real-Time SPA, custom component-based Javascript framework, React JS .NET REST API, HTML5/CSS3

Marvel, New York, NY

Feb 2013 - Oct 2013

Front-End Software Engineer (Consultant)

- Led R&D, architecture, and front-end development of Marvel.com, one of the first high-traffic fully-responsive websites.
- Co-invented new technology that dramatically reduces payload size sent to devices.
- Led in key initiatives, meetings, setting standards, methodologies, and processes.
- Wrote automated CI/CD testing suite specially designed for Marvel.com.
- Tech: Javascript, HTML5/CSS3, PHP

Software Engr. Consultant, Self-Employed

Jun 2009 - Apr 2014

- Developed applications for small to medium sized businesses, and a Fortune 500 company.
- BA, Requirement Gathering, Proposals, Specifications. Worked directly with clients.
- Saw projects through from conception to production.

NextEMR, New York, NY

Apr 2006 - Jun 2009

Co-Founder, Lead Software Engineer

- Led business analysis, UX, design, and full-stack development of the first UX-centric, web-based EMR (Electronic Health Record) apps.
- Acquired in 2009

Digitas, New York, NY Web Developer

Sep 2005 - Jan 2006

Developed microsites and emails for American Express, Delta, New York Times, Time Warner and others.

EDUCATION & ACCREDITATIONS

Computer Science - University at Buffalo, Buffalo, NY, 2003-2005 Private Pilot (SEL) - Federal Aviation Administration, 2015